Guide to the Executive Budget Committee Minutes 1990-2003
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Executive Budget Committee Minutes
1990-2003
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Archives 355
2.5 Linear feet of shelf space 3 boxes
The Executive Budget for Washington State University comprises both a capital budget for new construction and similar projects, and an operating budget for existing and new research and educational programs. The collection contains of minutes, agendas, and supplementary materials from meeting of the WSU Executive Budget Committee during the 1990-2003 fiscal years.
The Executive Budget for Washington State University comprises both a capital budget for new construction and similar projects, and an operating budget for existing and new research and educational programs. WSU's Executive Budget Committee consisted of higher level members of the Budget Office, the Provost's Office, and similar positions, and was responsible for proposing the Executive Budget for submission to the governor and legislature, and for adjusting these plans based on funding the legislature was willing to give the university. Circa the year 2000, the Executive Budget Committee transitioned into a Budget Council. The same process appears to exist as of 2016, though the term "executive budget" is no longer used; it's simply the "biennial operating and capital budget." A formal Budget Council no longer exists; it is unclear when it was discontinued.
The collection contains of minutes, agendas, and supplementary materials from meeting of the WSU Executive Budget Committee during the 1990-2003 fiscal years. The committee dealt with most of WSU's higher-level budget functions, including operating budgets, biennial budget requests to the legislature, budget allocation, retirement funding, and accruals.
The collection is organized chronologically, by date of meetings.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The materials in this collection were transferred to MASC by BJ Carlson of Washington State University's Budget Office on February 19, 2016, and retained as accession UA2016-02. Additonal materials were transferred to MASC by Emily Green of the Budget Office on November 23, 2016, and retained as accession UA2016-14.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University. Executive Budget Committee -- Records and correspondence.; Washington State University. Budget Office -- Records and correspondence.; Washington State University -- Finance.; Washington State University -- Appropriations and expenditures.
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- 1990, October-December (Box 1, Volume 1)
- 1991, January-June (Box 1, Volume 2)
- 1991, July-August (Box 1, Volume 3)
- 1991, September-December (Box 1, Volume 4)
- 1992, January-March (Box 1, Volume 5)
- 1992, April-May (Box 1, Volume 6)
- 1992, June-September (Box 1, Volume 7)
- 1992, October-December (Box 1, Volume 8)
- 1993, January-March (Box 1, Volume 9)
- 1993, April-June (Box 1, Volume 10)
- 1993, July-December (Box 1, Volume 11)
- 1994, January-March (Box 1, Volume 12)
- 1994, April-July (Box 1, Volume 13)
- 1994, August-December (Box 1, Volume 14)
- 1995, January-April (Box 1, Volume 15)
- 1995, May-September (Box 1, Volume 16)
- 1995, October-December (Box 1, Volume 17)
- 1996, January-March (Box 1, Volume 18)
- 1996, April-July (Box 2, Volume 1)
- 1996, August-October (Box 2, Volume 2)
- 1996, November-December (Box 2, Volume 3)
- 1997, January-February (Box 2, Volume 4)
- 1997, March-April (Box 2, Volume 5)
- 1997, May-June (Box 2, Volume 6)
- 1997, July-August (Box 3, Volume 1)
- 1997, September-October (Box 3, Volume 2)
- 1997, November-December (Box 3, Volume 3)
- 1998, January-March (Box 3, Volume 4)
- 1998, May-August (Box 3, Volume 5)
- 2000, March-May (Box 3, Volume 6)
- 2000, June-July (Box 3, Volume 7)
- 2000, August (Box 3, Volume 8)
- 2000, October-December (Box 3, Volume 9)
- 2001, January-February (Box 3, Volume 10)
- 2001, August-October (Box 3, Volume 11)
- 2001, November-December (Box 3, Volume 12)
- 2002, January-March (Box 3, Volume 13)
- 2002, April-May (Box 3, Volume 14)
- 2002, July-September (Box 3, Volume 15)
- 2002, October-December (Box 3, Volume 16)
- 2003, January-March (Box 3, Volume 17)
- 2003, April-May (Box 3, Volume 18)
- 2003, November (Box 3, Volume 19)